

CONTACT

• 00201000808240

✓ Amelhelaal0@gmail.com

https://amel-helel.vercel.app/

EDUCATION

2019 - 2021

 Bachelor of Business Administration

DIPLOMA IN FASHION AND DESIGN - CANADIAN CHAMBER OF COMMERCE, MIDDLE EAST

HOBBIES

- Fashion and textiles exploration
- Window display design for showrooms
- Traveling and exploring new cultures

SKILLS

- Ability to follow trends
- Strong attention to detail
- Excellent color sense
- Team player with strong communication skills
- Effective Communication

LANGUAGES

- Arabic (Native)
- English (Good)

AMEL ELSAYED HELAL

FASHION DESIGNER

ABOUT ME

Hello, I'm Amel.

I'm a creative fashion designer interested in art since I was a child.

I was born and raised in Saudi Arabia, then I moved to Egypt.

I have over 4 years of experience in fashion design. I'm skilled in creating powerful designs and selecting fabrics.

I have a successful history of collaborating with clients.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Atelier Manager A&H Couture House

2022 - 2024

- Scheduled and coordinated meetings, appointments, and travel plans.
- Typed documents, drafts, and emails.
- Assisted customers by drawing sketches and creating dress designs based on their requests.
- Collaborated with the team to analyze designs and meet client requirements.
- Help when fitting client's dresses and make notes

Fashion Designer

2021 - 2022

Burda Atelier

- Researched seasonal trends, colors, and raw materials to align with buyers' needs.
- · Assisted in selecting fabrics for dresses.
- Research and discover new trends and analyzing date with teamwork
- Created dress sketches tailored to clients' preferences.
- Coordinated the selection of models and locations for dress photo shoots.

Fashion Designer Assistant

2020 - 2021

Malton Bridal Wedding

- Took client measurements and made detailed notes for design adjustments.
- Fabric and materials selection according to what's suitable to design
- Created hand-drawn sketches, developed patterns, and analyzed trends in fabrics, colors, and shapes.
- Create wedding design dresses Specializing in high-end, luxury couture bridal materials and handcrafted details.
- Assisted brides throughout the design and fitting process.

Freelance Fashion Designer

2019 - 2020

- Draped materials to create powerful and innovative designs.
- Designed window displays for showrooms.
- Prepared design concepts, including sketches, fabric selections, and color choices.

COURSES AND TRAINING:

Fashion Design : Skilled in sketching, draping, pattern making, sewing, and styling

Makeup Certification: Completed training at Artist Academy

English Course: : Studied at the British Council